I'll start by getting rid of
Mitsuru's things.
As part of sorting out my emotions.
You met each other
at a wedding ceremony, right?
When we met, I was wearing this.
Ah, the pizza's here.
Coming!
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Sorry.
I threw away your slippers.
It's okay. I'm wearing socks.
Okay.
A guest?
A guest.
Is it okay for me to be here?
It's really you.
Is there a fake me?
That comeback is so you, Mitsuru.
Mr. Sonoda is here.
Mrs. Sonoda's husband?
Yes, right.
So the Sonoda you mentioned is Mrs. Sonoda?
Is it okay for me to be here?
Sorry.
I felt like I should be the one
to hit you first after all.
Next might be a fist.
Make sure you clench your teeth.
Okay.
Mrs. Seo.
About the bath towels,
- the thick and the thin one, which one is...
- Oh, the bath towels...
This one is mine.
Nice to meet you.
My wife has been in your care.
Likewise.
Oh, the pizza...
Coming!
[Episode 6]
I'll make some tea.
- Oh, I'm fine.
- Huh?
I need to go pick up Sho soon.
Ah...
I think you two should talk first.
- Okay.
- Thank you for having me.
I'm sorry.
I don't really understand
the situation either.
I see.
I'm sorry.
I'll arrange a proper meeting another day,
and get him to explain.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Likewise.
I almost punched him just now.
So I'll step away for a bit and cool down.
I'm really sorry.
Thank you for having me.
Argh!
Do you want some too, Sakiko?
Yes.
Okay.
What are you thinking about right now?
I want to go pay my respects
at Mrs. Sonoda's house,
but I don't think today
is the best time for that.
Besides, her husband is in that state.
You're so calm.
Am I?
I'm thinking about what to ask you first.
There's so much I want to ask,
so my head is a mess.
You look calm.
Well, I am an adult, after all.
Mr. Sonoda too.
He spoke calmly because he's an adult.
He didn't hit anyone.
An adult crying and screaming,
or raising a hand, that's a big deal.
You earlier, Sakiko,
were at that point.
Yeah.
I also thought it would be okay to hit you.
I see.
So...
How do you feel now?
Feel?
What emotions are you feeling right now?
I'm a little relieved.
- That you didn't get hit?
- No.
I'm relieved to see you
and Mrs. Sonoda's husband
looking well.
Do you know what I'm feeling right now?
Mostly anger...
I guess.
Correct.
I'm angry.
Yeah.
But...
It's not just that. So I'm troubled.
If it was just anger, it'd be fine.
If I could have grabbed you
by the collar, choked you,
if I could have stabbed you with a knife,
that would've been better.
For me too,
I'm relieved that you're looking well.
And I'm happy that you came back.
But...
I'm scared to ask you what happened,
and I'm worried about Mr. Sonoda too.
I'd rather you just hadn't come back.
But I'm also happy you came back.
Happy to see you.
And overall, I feel angry.
Seeing you acting all nonchalant like that
really makes me angry.
I'm sorry.
For what?
Going missing?
For Azusa?
Don't go to Mr. Sonoda's house by yourself.
Wait for when it's convenient for them,
and I'll go with you.
Okay.
Daddy!
You're here! Welcome back!
Daddy, you stink.
Huh?
I can't seem to get by without smoking.
Did something bad happen?
Yes.
Are you okay?
No.
You can smoke if you want.
It's okay.
You always want to smoke
when you drink coffee.
It's fine. I won't get mad at you
at a time like this.
I'm already pretty mad anyway.
I won't get mad about that.
No.
I quit. I haven't smoked for a year.
Really?
What business did you have in Nagano?
I went to see my parents.
Then that address...
That's my parents' house.
I've been living there
with them this past year.
Are you okay?
The person you met
at that house was my mother.
I'm sorry.
I told her that if someone
named Sakiko Seo came,
she should pretend to not know anything,
no matter what you said.
My father was there too.
He passed away recently, though.
They're both indifferent people,
but when my father died,
my mother was really devastated,
and that's when I remembered you.
I disappeared so suddenly,
I got worried about you
and how you were doing.
Naoto came to help with the funeral,
so I asked him then to arrange for me
- to be able to talk to you on the phone.
- Wait.
That's a lot of info.
Or rather, the rest,
I'll hear the rest together with Mr. Sonoda.
Otherwise, you'd have to explain twice.
- Okay.
- What are your plans for today?
Are you staying over?
Well, it is your house,
so I'm assuming you'll stay.
Your underwear and stuff are in there.
Yeah.
Sorry, I was about to throw them away.
It's fine.
Can I smoke?
Sure, I guess.
I can't taste anything at all.
I'm going shopping. Need anything?
Though it's just the usual supermarket.
I'm fine.
There isn't any sweet cheese.
I don't eat it, so I didn't buy any.
Okay, then I want some.
I'm off.
It's fine, you can eat that.
Okay, thanks.
Take care.
Yeah.
No matter how much we explain our feelings,
it still feels like something
is off from the truth.
Mitsuru went to see his parents.
He's been living with them for the past year.
He had quit smoking.
I felt like everything ever since
our first encounter was being denied.
And now, from the couple,
a bouquet of gratitude for the parents!
It's nice how close they are
as families, huh?
Yeah, it is.
And now, the bride, Ami,
has written a letter
expressing her gratitude to her parents.
I'm stepping out, just to the bathroom.
- Huh? Now?
- Sorry, I can't hold it.
Dad, Mom...
They're reading the letter to Ami's parents
right now. It's a good part.
Yes.
Even though it's a good part,
is it still okay to leave?
I...
I ran away.
Ah, same here.
- Same?
- Yes, I find those things unpleasant.
Whether I'm there or not,
it doesn't make any difference.
And I'd feel bad disturbing those
who are genuinely moved.
Right.
Are you from the groom's side?
I'm from the company.
I'm a high school classmate of Ami's.
Will you go back
after you finish that cigarette?
Yes. Though I don't really have to go back.
I get it.
I'm not exactly dying to go back either.
I dread the after-party.
Yeah, the after-party really is a drag.
Will the parents attend that too?
Seems like it.
Like, it seems like
they're all quite close as families.
Seriously? That stinks.
Yeah, I totally get it.
I wonder if she's done reading yet?
Yeah.
Wanna go somewhere? Just the two of us?
Oh, don't go back.
Like, maybe we could go get a drink?
If we suddenly disappear,
everyone will worry.
Right, sorry.
Well, then.
Well...
would here be okay?
Huh?
I'll be waiting here after the after-party.
It's close by.
Okay.
I'll have one more cigarette
and then head back.
What a weird guy.
Congratulations on your wedding.
But in a group, he seemed normal.
He blended in naturally.
I thought he was a weird guy
who could act normal.
- Shall we go? Let's go.
- Huh? Okay, let's go.
Welcome.
Oh, thanks for coming.
Even if we're not having fun,
we end up pretending to be.
It's no use sulking.
Exactly.
In the end, it's easier to just
act like an adult.
But sneaking out like that...
Yeah.
I just couldn't handle it today.
Another one, please.
Certainly.
It's not that we clicked especially well.
But strangely, we never
ran out of things to talk about.
And the occasional
little silences were comfortable.
I talked about 60% of the time,
he talked about 40%.
You're not very good with
those kinds of letters.
Yeah.
Me neither.
I'm not really that close with my parents.
How should I put it?
It's not exactly out of jealousy,
but... well, maybe it is out of jealousy?
Whenever I see a close family,
I feel like I'm missing something.
That's it.
I feel like I'm defective.
It's painful to watch them.
Close families, people who are
good to their parents,
parents who cherish their kids, all of that.
Yes.
That's exactly it.
It was a feeling I'd had for years,
but never been able to put into words.
I'm estranged from my parents.
I haven't seen them in about 15 years.
They're indifferent people,
so if I don't reach out,
we become strangers in no time.
Huh.
In my case, my mom is overly controlling,
and she pushes things on me thinking
they're good for me, even if I hate them.
And if I reject them,
she either cries or gets hysterical.
And just when I think she's calmed down,
she starts this big speech about how hard
it was to give birth to me and raise me.
A long lecture.
Huh.
That must be painful too.
Like you're the bad one for not accepting it.
Yes.
You're listening to me.
- Yes.
- For me,
in second grade, that was the first time
I thought my mom might be weird.
She tried to pick and choose my friends.
I could share this feeling with him.
I was happy.
I wish I had an older sibling.
Someone to look up to, I guess.
Right. Like, under these parents,
how to live, and how things become.
Like a sample?
Exactly.
That doesn't sound very nice, though.
Are you taking the train home?
- Yes.
- Then shall we head out soon?
Okay.
- Check, please.
- Yes, thank you.
You can treat me next time.
Next time?
Yes.
Okay.
Maybe what was missing
in my past relationships
was this feeling.
With this person,
I might be able to have a real family.
On our third date, he suddenly proposed.
It's Sakiko, right? Your first name?
- Yes.
- Between Little Saki and Sacchan,
which do you prefer?
When I was little,
people called me Little Saki.
Friends?
Most friends called me Saki,
and relatives and neighbors
called me Little Saki.
Then I'll call you Sacchan.
Oh, okay.
Then I guess that's settled.
Even before we dropped the formal speech,
he called me Sacchan.
[When can we meet next?]
Just when I thought it might be going well,
he stopped contacting me.
One month passed,
two months passed,
and three months passed.
Maybe he didn't like
that I still called him Mr. Seo?
My nails may have been
a bit too flashy last time.
Maybe ordering dessert
before being asked was a mistake.
I regretted stupid little things.
I suppose this could be
a side effect of love.
[Mitsuru Seo: Sorry for the delay.]
[I just got back from an overseas
business trip. I'd love to see you again.]
Sorry.
[Mitsuru Seo: Sorry for the delay.]
[I just got back from an overseas
business trip. I'd love to see you again.]
One notification on my phone,
and I was in a good mood.
It was already love.
We started dating
when 'Mr. Seo' became 'Mr. Mitsuru',
and right after we got married,
'Mr. Mitsuru' became just 'Mitsuru'.
We didn't have a wedding ceremony.
We wanted to start our family
with just the two of us.
You don't have to force yourself
to wear it normally.
No, I'll wear it.
It's a way to silently show
that we're married.
Isn't that pretty convenient?
I know, I thought the same thing.
Right?
Good.
I didn't want to force you to wear it.
I had a feeling that
we could become a family.
- Sacchan.
- Hmm?
Is it here?
The little frictions of living together
were all within expectations,
and we could easily resolve them by talking.
- Hey.
- Hmm?
Is it the pumpkin?
Sorry, but I don't like pumpkin.
Sorry.
We had only one rule.
No lying.
But neither of us had to talk about anything
that we didn't want to talk about.
It was simple.
I'll have my baby and come back healthy.
What was hard was
no longer being just the two of us.
Welcome back.
Three is better than two,
and four is better than three.
I imagined too much that it was
what a family should be like.
[Pregnancy test]
Even though we were happy
as just two, I got greedy.
I'm also happy with just the two of us.
Just three more days' worth.
I'll finish these off.
Thank you.
Whoa!
We bought a house just for the two of us.
This feels good.
Nice, isn't it?
We were happy.
I thought we could live together forever
in this house, just the two of us.
I really thought we could.
What did we do wrong?
What was wrong with me?
Or...
did you find another right answer?
Welcome back.
I'm home.
That must have been heavy, right? Thanks.
Did you clean the floor?
Yeah, lightly.
Thanks.
That thing's not doing very well, is it?
Yeah, it's been like that for a while.
It stops as soon as you move it a bit.
Is it on its last legs?
Probably.
The warranty period for repairs has passed.
Five years?
Yeah.
Even though we paid an extra
2,000 yen or something, that's expired too.
I see.
I tried cleaning the filter,
but it was totally clean.
You mean for the washing machine?
Huh? No, for the vacuum cleaner.
Oh.
Is there anything else you need done?
Places you can't reach?
Oh, what about the winter clothes?
Did you put them on the top shelf?
Sacchan?
This is what I wanted.
Just the two of us here,
talking about boring stuff like this forever.
About food, appliances.
I thought this would go on forever.
Since it's not related to Mr. Sonoda,
there's something I want to ask you
while it's just the two of us.
Okay.
What did you dislike about me?
Is it because of kids?
Okay, if not then what?
- Sacchan...
- Saying that I didn't do anything wrong,
that's the worst.
Because it means that
there's nothing I can do.
It means that you found someone else,
someone who isn't me.
That's the worst.
I see, that's it.
That's it, isn't it?
Where's your ring?
I have it.
I just don't wear it.
Mrs. Seo.
Oh, Mr. Sonoda.
You startled me.
Doing laundry?
No, you aren't, are you?
Yeah.
Just taking a walk, I guess.
Ah, same here.
Where's Mitsuru?
At home.
I get restless when we're alone together.
Yeah, I bet.
It was so sudden.
I know we have to talk,
but the things I want to ask
are scary and hard to ask.
I ask a little, get really shaken, explode,
and that led to this walk.
I'm scared to hear the details too.
Yes.
Oh, how's Sho?
My sister's looking after him.
He had swimming today,
so he went to sleep right away.
He said he'll show me
the butterfly stroke next time.
What's that about? When's that gonna be?
Well, he can't do it yet.
He was talking about it
like it's his specialty.
Huh?
I feel calm when I'm with you, Mr. Sonoda.
Oh, I didn't mean anything deep by that.
No, I know.
It's just as you said.
No fluttering or restlessness.
That's right.
I'm sorry.
Well, being laughed at is a little annoying.
I'm grateful that
nothing can shake my heart.
I'm of that same mindset now.
You alone don't shake my heart, Mrs. Seo.
Me alone?
Honestly, whatever happens,
Azusa isn't coming back,
so I thought that if this could continue,
that would be nice.
Every Saturday,
talking nonsense with you here,
and occasionally having dinner with Sho too.
I guess I'm just wishing for
the impossible again.
I was thinking about
tracking him down and punching him,
but when he actually showed up...
Mitsuru...
He didn't say there was anything
about me that he disliked.
Which means it's about Azusa.
And if that's the case,
we need to talk,
with you included, Mr. Sonoda.
When should we do it? The talk.
Though it's not really a talk, is it?
More like an interrogation.
Mrs. Seo.
Hmm?
Did you cry?
Yes.
Earlier...
And pretty hard.
Did you get angry?
Yes.
Oh, I didn't mention this before,
but I...
I hit him first.
Though it was just a slap.
Oh, then...
I'm glad.
Sorry.
How about tomorrow night?
Better to do it sooner.
I'll figure out something for Sho.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Every year?
- Yes.
Welcome back.
I'm home.
Good night.
Please take care of it.
Well, Chizuru?
Shall we meet at the usual place tonight?
There's so much I want to talk about,
I feel like I have to finish work
right now and go drinking,
but I'll try to hold out
until the end of the day.
Oh, sorry.
Tonight's not going to work.
Huh?
Sorry, I just really need a rain check.
What? Did Mitsuru come home or something?
I won't accept any excuse less than that.
That's it.
Huh?
He came home.
I'm glad you're okay.
Well, I did get slapped.
You could have been stabbed, you know.
Thank goodness Sacchan is an adult
who can keep her cool.
In this kind of situation,
that kind of phrasing
can really make people angry.
Please choose your words more carefully.
This past year,
the number of people
I interacted with drastically decreased,
so it seems my communication skills
have gotten worse.
Even though I've survived
just thanks to my good external appearance.
I'm glad that you've been here, Naoto.
If you hadn't been here,
I might not have run away.
Or if I had run away,
I might have come back sooner.
So from Sakiko's perspective,
that means it would have been better
if I hadn't been here.
It would've turned out
like this eventually anyway.
How long has it been? How long really?
It was right around when I met Sacchan.
About ten years ago.
That's amazing, isn't it?
No, Sakiko is the amazing one.
Thanks to her, I was able to stay
in one place for this long.
Look.
You're good.
I'll give it to the old man.
I didn't bring any gifts.
Is this okay?
I'll buy something on the way back.
Give this to the old man too.
Okay.
Sho, if you could talk to Mommy,
what would you say?
Anything?
Yeah, anything.
Mommy!
You're back!
Right?
See, there's the old man.
- Hello.
- Oh, you're here.
- This is for you.
- Oh, for me?
Well, this is a bit clumsy,
just like your mom.
But it has character. Thank you.
All right, then,
please look after him for a bit.
I wonder if it'll turn into a bloodbath.
Tell me about it later.
Let's do our best.
Okay, Mitsuru, please answer everything
you're asked properly.
Got it.
Why was my wife with you that day?
I heard you were going to see your parents.
Why was my wife accompanying you
for something like that?
I don't think it'd be relevant
to have her along.
About a year before the accident,
I met Mrs. Sonoda at the laundromat,
and we often talked
on the third Friday of every month.
And?
When I met her the day before the accident,
I told her that the next day,
I was planning to go to my parents' house.
And?
So the next day, she went to Nagano with me.
That's not a reason at all.
Yeah, that's right.
I'm sorry.
- So...
- Did you ask her to go with you?
Mitsuru, did you ask her to go along?
Yes, that's right.
Why?
I felt nervous.
Forget it, I'll just ask you directly,
without choosing words.
All right.
You were having an affair, weren't you?
That's right, isn't it? I'm sorry.
Does saying "I'm sorry" mean you admit it?
No, I'm saying there was a possibility
that you might think that,
and I was somewhat aware of that.
So it's not true?
There was no affair.
- Then what...
- It's as I said.
Every month, we met and talked
at the laundromat. That's it.
The day of the accident was the first time
we met outside the laundromat.
So you expect me to just believe
that it wasn't an affair?
Even if that's what you say,
I'm just telling you the facts.
Do you have any way to prove that?
Right, where's the proof?
I'm sure there are plenty of ways to prove
that two people are having an affair,
but proof that there wasn't
any affair is a bit...
So because my wife is dead,
you think you can just say whatever you want
and get away with it?
That's a bit of a stretch.
A grown man and woman, keeping
their meetings secret from their partners,
meeting on a set day
every month at a set place,
and in the end,
you took her with you for an event
like visiting your estranged parents.
And you're saying there was
nothing deep between you?
- Hey!
- So you think she was the kind of person
who would have an affair?
Mitsuru, wait.
You don't trust her, do you?
I feel sorry for you.
- Excuse me?
- Just because a man and a woman are together,
you jump to the conclusion that it's romance?
That's prejudice. Must be tough.
Were you forcing that on Mrs. Sonoda too?
And you, a pitiful person who lost his wife,
you think you can just ignore the facts,
flaunt your prejudice,
and force your values on others?
I'm sorry, I slapped him first. Again.
I understand what you want to say,
but as for why Azusa isn't here right now,
you know whose fault that is, right?
This person is Azusa's husband.
Don't forget that.
You need to choose your words more carefully.
I'm sorry.
I was just feeling uneasy
about visiting my parents
for the first time in a while,
so I asked her to come along. That's all.
But at the service area on the way
where we stopped,
I thought that if I was going to run away,
that was the moment.
Run away?
I'll explain to you properly later,
about running away.
You probably won't understand,
but I'll explain.
I'm sorry I was the only one who survived.
Can I ask you something too?
What exactly is your relationship?
Well, it's not like we have a relationship,
I mean, it's nothing.
She's helped me out with my son Sho,
and I've gotten a lot of support from her.
That goes both ways.
There are a lot of things
I can't do alone, so he helps me out.
No, no, I haven't really done anything.
You know, because
our situations were similar,
there were many things we both understood,
and we'd talk about them.
Yes, that's all.
Isn't that what you'd call a relationship?
- No, it's not.
- Why would that make us have an affair?
Where's the proof of that?
How can you prove
that there was no romantic involvement?
You went into her house, didn't you?
You helped her dispose of
my personal belongings, didn't you?
You met with her last night, didn't you?
Have you never been alone together
in a private room?
Can you prove you were always
with someone else?
How do you prove that nothing happened?
That's exactly the same as
what you're charging me with now.
How can you two be so sure
that it's not an affair?
You were so suspicious of me and Mrs. Sonoda.